Alejandro Beltran

Email: alebelcor@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/alebelcor ♂ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alebelcor 더

I'm a Software Engineer from Mexico focused on Web Front End with 10+ years of experience with a specialty and passion for UI, Web performance, and Web accessibility.

Experience

• ConsumerTrack, Inc. ♂ Front End Engineer (Remote) via Encora

Apr 2020 - Present

- ∘ Focused on Front End Engineering for ImportantScore.com ♂ and GOFreeCredit.com ♂ that offer consumers fast and easy online access to their credit score and credit monitoring services via the three national credit bureaus: Experian, Equifax, and TransUnion
- Led Web performance efforts to improve our performance score and Web Vitals, as part of our team mission, which has resulted in a 68% (mobile) and 17% (desktop) increase in performance score points for GOFreeCredit.com. And a 43% (mobile) and 17% (desktop) increase for ImportantScore.com.
- o Implemented several other performances optimizations: next-gen image formats, image optimizations, visible text during webfont load, reduced requests size, eliminated dead dependencies, added resource hints, asynchronous/lazy loading of render-blocking resources.
- Implemented A/B tests and experiments to determine the most successful variation to integrate and help increase revenue, gross profit, GPM, and various other C2C rates.
- Implemented automation of data management for CCPA compliance and to reduce the manual work of over 600 inquiries per month for "Delete My Data", "See My Data" and "Do Not Sell My Data" requests.

Tech: JavaScript, React, Redux, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Sass (SCSS), Twig, Bootstrap, Node.js, npm, Jest, React Testing Library, Babel, ESLint, Husky, Webpack, CircleCI, jQuery, PostCSS, Visual Studio Code, Git

American Tours International, LLC Front End Engineer (Remote)

via Nearsoft

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020*

- Led an engineering team of two in charge of implementing a modern, fast, and aesthetic re-imagining of ATI's internal administration tool used by travel agents for payment and transaction review, and processing.
- Designed the shapes, payload/content, and headers of the HTTP API requests and responses.
- o Implemented pure client-side user session management.
- o Implemented auto-refresh mechanism of JWT token.
- Implemented data tables with pagination, sorting, expandable rows with sub-component rendering.
- Implemented custom column filters for tables, e.g. text, date (with date picker widget), number range, and select.
- Implemented test suite with 90% code coverage for actions/components/hooks/reducers/selectors/services/utils.
- Implemented maintainable and customizable CSS architecture using Sass, Bootstrap (with overrides), and BEM.
- Implemented mock back end API server using Express for faster and better DX.
- Integrated code linting and auto-formatting for JS/JSX files as part of test suite, and VS Code.

Tech: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass (SCSS), React, React Bootstrap, React Router, Reselect, Jest, React Testing Library, Create React App, PropTypes, Node.js, Express, ESLint, Prettier, Husky, Yarn, date-fns, Visual Studio Code, SVN with git-svn

* - Project ended due to COVID-19.

Software Engineer (Remote)

Switchfly, LLC ♂

via Nearsoft

o Implemented interstitial/loading page for better SEO and accessibility.

Feb 2014 – Aug 2019

- Implemented custom responsive navigation with auto-collapsing items based on viewport.
- Increased performance by implementing preloading of the next page assets.
- Increased performance by reducing/consolidating-and compression-of Ajax HTTP requests/responses.
- o Integrated PAYBACK® ♂ and Masterpass™ ♂ payments into checkout process.
- o Added automated end-to-end test cases for all new features in Selenium Java.
- Added base, and custom analytics for clients, for data-based product and UI/UX decision making.
- Refactored codebase to meet AA level of the WCAG 2.0 accessibility standard.
- Peer-reviewed other people's code as "Subject Matter Expect" of the shopping experience.

Tech: JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS, Sass (SCSS), Ember.js, Handlebars.js, Git, Gulp, JSHint, Karma, Mocha, Chai, npm, jQuery, Selenium, Jenkins, Ant, Maven, FreeMarker, ColdFusion, PostgreSQL, IntelliJ IDEA

Evolve Media, LLC t
Senior Software Engineer (Remote)
Software Engineer (Remote)

via Intugo Jul 2013 – Feb 2014

Jul 2012 - Jul 2013

- Worked as Software Engineer focused on Front End Engineering for multiple heavily trafficked and highly ranked websites targeting, among other things: women, fashion, sports, gaming and entertainment.
- ㅇ Examples: the Fashion Spot & , Momtastic & , SuperHero Hype &

Tech: JavaScript, PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS with Sass (SCSS), Compass, and Susy, jQuery, SVN with git-svn, Jenkins, Ant, npm, Grunt, JSHint, Capistrano

• OptumInsight ♂ Application Development Engineer (Remote)

via Nearsoft

Jan 2009 – Jun 2012

 Worked as Application Development Engineer extending and maintaining their EMR Lite system, related services and applications.

Tech: Java, Java EE, Servlets, JavaScript, LotusScript, Formula Language, Lotus Notes, Lotus Domino, Tomcat, HTML, CSS, XML, XPath, XSLT, SVN, CVS, RCS, Maven, Ant, Make, Jenkins

Education

• Hermosillo Institute of Technology Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering Hermosillo, MX Dec 2008

Certifications

• Responsive Web Design

freeCodeCamp

• JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

freeCodeCamp

• Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (TLSZSQSVHG-MMSTYQSQ-RPFDLKRHJT)

Scrum Foundation

Skills

- Software Engineering: Agile Software Development, Software Release Cycle, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, End-to-end Testing, Continuous Integration, Software Security, Static Code Analysis
- Front End (Web): HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Web Performance, Web Accessibility, React, React Hooks, Redux, CSS-in-JS, Sass (SCSS), Bootstrap
- Tools: Node.js, npm, Yarn, ESLint, Prettier, Jest, React Testing Library, Git, Visual Studio Code